Guide to the Dick Thornburgh Papers, 1932- AIS.1998.30.12
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Director, Institute of Politics, John F. Kennedy School of Government, Harvard University, 1987-1988; XII.
  - Boards and Memberships, 1987-1988; 10.
    - Letters and Requests to Join
      - Commonwealth Foundation, December, 1987-July, 1988 (Box 734, Folder 9)
      - Mid-Atlantic Legal Foundation, January, 1986-May, 1987 (Box 734, Folder 10)
      - Smith Richardson Foundation, August, 1986-September, 1987 (Box 734, Folder 11)
      - Twentieth Century Club, July, 1987-March, 1988 (Box 734, Folder 12)
  - Kirkpatrick and Lockhart (K & L), 1987-1988; 11.
    In addition to becoming Director of the Institute of Politics (IOP), Thornburgh also rejoined his former law firm, Kirkpatrick and Lockhart (K & L), which had opened an office in Boston. He also served on a number of university, company and organization boards of trustees. His balancing of these varied commitments continued until he was asked to serve as Attorney General of the United States in July 1988. He resigned from IOP and again from K & L in August of 1988, just over a year after starting at IOP and rejoining K & L.
    The Kirkpatrick and Lockhart files are divided into two sections. The first of these is firm administrative files from 1987-1988, memoranda to partners, and material from meetings and events. The second section contains Thornburgh's personal files, including memoranda to and from him, personal and professional correspondence, notes, telephone logs and schedules. Many of these materials are annotated by Thornburgh.
    Researchers should be aware that the K & L files are related to the IOP files only in that they were produced in the same time period. The same is true with the "Boards and Memberships" files and the "Ginny Thornburgh at Harvard University" files. Because the time at IOP spans only a year, it is relevant to group these separate yet simultaneously produced materials together.
    - Kirkpatrick and Lockhart (K & L) Administrative Files
      - Informational Materials and Memoranda to Partners and Lawyers
        - Fact sheet and informational booklet on firm, February, 1987 (Box 735, Folder 1)
        - Memos to partners and lawyers, January, 1986-July, 1988 (Box 735, Folder 2-4)
        - Memoranda regarding Harrisburg office, January, 1987-March, 1988 (Box 735, Folder 5)
        - Newsletters, calendars, news clippings and articles, and financial summaries, 1987-1988 (Box 735, Folder 6)
      - Partners Meetings
        - Memos, reports and agendas, 1987-1988 (Box 735, Folder 7-16)
      - Reports and Newsletters
        - New Matter Report: informational packets regarding clients, December, 1987-June, 1988 (Box 735, Folder 17)
        - "Washington Watch" newsletter, 1987 (Box 735, Folder 18)
      - Clients and Cases
        - Bethlehem Steel, January-September, 1987 (Box 736, Folder 1)
        - Children's Rehabilitation Center, October, 1987-May, 1988 (Box 736, Folder 2)
        - Christos Painting, April-July, 1988 (Box 736, Folder 3)
        - Cranston Securities Company, February, 1987 (Box 736, Folder 4)
        - Ecogen, 1986-1987 (Box 736, Folder 5)
        - Edison Electric Institute (EEI), March, 1987 (Box 736, Folder 6)
        - General Carbide Corporation, July-September, 1987 (Box 736, Folder 7)
        - Glimcher-Zamagias Group, August-October, 1987 (Box 736, Folder 8)
        - Koppers, April, 1988 (Box 736, Folder 9)
        - Nuclear matters, February-March, 1987 (Box 736, Folder 10)
        - Quadrex Group, April-November, 1987 (Box 736, Folder 11)
        - St. Barnabas, Inc., March-April, 1987 (Box 736, Folder 12)
        - United Medical Management, January-August, 1987 (Box 737, Folder 1)
        - West End Health Center, March, 1988 (Box 737, Folder 2)
      - Events
        - Press conference: Thornburgh to join law firm, February 2, 1987 (Box 737, Folder 3)
        - Washington, DC office trip, February 11-12, 1987 (Box 737, Folder 4)
        - Boston reception honoring Thornburgh, March 3, 1987 (Box 737, Folder 5)
        - 1987 Summer Associate orientation, April 4, 1987 (Box 737, Folder 6)
        - Miami reception honoring Thornburgh, April 28, 1987 (Box 737, Folder 7)
        - Partner and spouse weekend, March 14-17, 1987 (Box 737, Folder 8)
        - Pennsylvania Bar Association Annual Meeting, May 15, 1987 (Box 737, Folder 9)
    - Thornburgh's Partner Files
      - Internal K & L memoranda regarding Thornburgh's return (annotated), January-February, 1987 (Box 737, Folder 10)
      - K & L memoranda to Thornburgh regarding cases and clients, February, 1987-March, 1988 (Box 737, Folder 11-12)
      - Memoranda from Thornburgh regarding cases and clients, February-September, 1987 (Box 737, Folder 13)
      - Partner correspondence to Thornburgh, February, 1986-July, 1988 (Box 737, Folder 14)
      - Client-related correspondence to and from Thornburgh, January-November, 1987 (Box 737, Folder 15)
      - Thornburgh correspondence to outside persons, February, 1987-April, 1988 (Box 737, Folder 16)
      - Thornburgh correspondence to outside persons regarding rejoining K & L, February, 1987 (Box 738, Folder 1)
      - Thornburgh correspondence: personal recommendation letters, March-June, 1987 (Box 738, Folder 2)
      - Thornburgh correspondence with media, February-June, 1987 (Box 738, Folder 3)
      - Thornburgh personal correspondence, February-April, 1987 (Box 738, Folder 4)
      - Thornburgh correspondence to members of the Thornburgh Governor administration, February 18, 1987 (Box 738, Folder 5)
      - Thornburgh biographies, February, 1987 (Box 738, Folder 6)
      - Petition for reinstatement to the Pennsylvania Supreme Court, 1987 (Box 738, Folder 7)
      - Telephone log, January-August, 1987 (Box 738, Folder 8)
      - Personal notes, 1987-1988 (Box 738, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous personal materials, including magazine articles, notes and memoranda, 1987-1988 (Box 738, Folder 10)
      - 1987 Calendars (Box 738, Folder 11)
      - Daily schedules, February, 1987-April, 1988 (Box 738, Folder 12)
      - Long range schedules, February, 1987-May, 1988 (Box 738, Folder 13)
      - Bound schedule books, 1987-1988 (Box 738, Folder 14-15)
      - Letter of resignation from K & L as a result of appointment as Attorney General of the United States, July 25, 1988 (Box 738, Folder 16)
      - Firm memorandum regarding Thornburgh's resignation and appointment as Attorney General of the United States, August 2, 1988 (Box 738, Folder 17)
      - K & L Bulletin: announcement of Thornburgh's appointment as Attorney General of the United States, August, 1988 (Box 738, Folder 18)
  - Ginny Thornburgh, Coordinator of Programs for Persons with Disabilities at Harvard University, 1987-1988; 12.
    While her husband, Dick Thornburgh, was serving as Director of the Institute of Politics, Ginny Thornburgh worked at Harvard University as the first disability coordinator, with the official title "Coordinator of Programs for People with Disabilities." She extended her long-standing personal commitment to disabled persons to a professional job, as an advocate for all disabled (physical, mental, or sensory) students, staff and faculty at the university.
    While there, she oversaw and edited the university's first guide to services for persons with disabilities, "Resources for Persons with Disabilities," in 1989. This guide is available here online.
    Researchers should be aware that the "Ginny Thornburgh at Harvard University" files are related to the IOP files only in that they were produced in the same time period. The same is true with Dick Thornburgh's "Boards and Memberships" and "K & L" files. Because the time at IOP spans only a year, it is convenient to group these separate yet simultaneously produced materials together.
    - Bio, articles and memoranda announcing appointment and about her work, February-May, 1988 (Box 738, Folder 19)
    - "Resources for Persons with Disabilities," Ginny Thornburgh and Sunny Macmillan, editors, published by Harvard University, 1989 (Box 738, Folder 20)